<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cybercrime on Learning is a lifelong journey, best traveled with an open mind and a curious heart.</title>
    <link>https://www.nephos.guru/tags/cybercrime/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cybercrime on Learning is a lifelong journey, best traveled with an open mind and a curious heart.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:27:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nephos.guru/tags/cybercrime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hospitals should only have to focus on saving lives; not on security</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/hospital_security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/hospital_security/</guid>
      <description>Hospitals should only have to focus on saving lives; not on security
I know that the above statement will offend a lot of people, but before you all start flaming me, let me elaborate on this more and provide you with context as to why I would make such a statement. This past Sunday, I had to take my wife to the ER which resulted in her having to have emergency surgery, and for anyone who has ever been in a hospital with a loved one, knows that it is a very stressful time and our focus and that of the hospital staff is on doing what they can for the patient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying One Step ahead of the Cybercriminals</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2020/one_step_ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2020/one_step_ahead/</guid>
      <description>Security seems to be the one area that each year we spend more money than we did the previous year to stay one step ahead of the threat. Yet, every year there seem to be more and more significant security breaches!
So, we ask for more money again, and the cycle repeats like a bad case of deja vu or is it just a &amp;ldquo;glitch in the Matrix&amp;rdquo;.
As with many things in life, it is not enough to know the rules, you need to understand how to play the game if you are to be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
