<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning is a lifelong journey, best traveled with an open mind and a curious heart.</title>
    <link>https://www.nephos.guru/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Learning is a lifelong journey, best traveled with an open mind and a curious heart.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:25:41 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nephos.guru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JupyterLab behind Nginx Reverse Proxy</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2023/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:25:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2023/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites This is based on the assumption on having a Virtual Machine / Cloud Instance that has the following:
Debian 12 Server (minimal installation with SSH enabled) A non-root user with sudo privileges Installing Dependencies Update Debian package index and install required packages:
sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt install python3 python3-pip python3-venv nodejs -y Confirm that these have been successfully installed by running command python3 --version &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pip3 --version &amp;amp;&amp;amp; node --version and you will see output as below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Linux Journey: From Desktop Environments to Minimalist Tiling Window Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2023/linux_journey_continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 18:22:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2023/linux_journey_continued/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been over two years since I made the switch from Apple to Linux. It was a great decision, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back.
At first, I used PopOS, a Linux distribution known for its tiling window manager. I liked PopOS, but I wanted a more customized and streamlined experience. So, I decided to move away from desktop environments altogether and switch to a tiling window manager on Debian 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/linux_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 01:32:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/linux_journey/</guid>
      <description>This is the story of my journey from being a loyal Apple user for nearly 20 years when 1 year ago I decided to completely leave the Apple ecosystem and move to Linux full-time.
The article will provide an overview of the many small decisions that I made from mid-2021 when I got a Lenovo laptop and installed PopOS 20.04 on it.
Background To provide some context, it was around 2000 when I decided to move away from Windows (the last good Windows OS in my opinion was Windows XP) and my first foray into Apple was an iMac (The tangerine colour I believe) and over the years I have had several MacBook Pros including the 17inch model which was a beast and lasted for more years than I can recall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 01:27:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/privacy/</guid>
      <description>I read this article today in which Google stated that it would &amp;ldquo;wipe user location history for visits to healthcare clinics, domestic violence shelters&amp;rdquo; with the following text as an example:
Suppose the company&amp;rsquo;s systems detect a visit to places including medical facilities, counseling centers, domestic violence shelters, abortion and fertility clinics, or addiction treatment centers. In that case, Fitzpatrick says, &amp;ldquo;we will delete these entries from Location History soon after they visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure is Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/failure_is_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 01:23:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/failure_is_learning/</guid>
      <description>I am sure that at some point in our lives we have all encountered failure and at this point, it may have felt that it was the worst thing that could happen. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t wish to get into the discussion about what type of failure is best, but from my perspective, I have been using this for the last few months to determine the best course of action for me to learn and how I can integrate failure to deepen learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have I been doing it wrong all these years?</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/notetaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/notetaking/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had one of those moments when you start to think that the system you have been using for years just isn&amp;rsquo;t working for you anymore?
I had that experience a few weeks ago when I was doing some personal studying on the weekend and while taking notes, I realised that there were several other projects that I was working on that could benefit from what I was learning and the application of it to these areas could be extremely beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospitals should only have to focus on saving lives; not on security</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/hospital_security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/hospital_security/</guid>
      <description>Hospitals should only have to focus on saving lives; not on security
I know that the above statement will offend a lot of people, but before you all start flaming me, let me elaborate on this more and provide you with context as to why I would make such a statement. This past Sunday, I had to take my wife to the ER which resulted in her having to have emergency surgery, and for anyone who has ever been in a hospital with a loved one, knows that it is a very stressful time and our focus and that of the hospital staff is on doing what they can for the patient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Cost of a Data Breach</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2021/real_cost_data_breach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 20:02:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2021/real_cost_data_breach/</guid>
      <description>Today we are in a situation that many have never faced before, and organisations of all sizes are looking at ways to cut costs. One area that I have seen is with regards to cybersecurity due to the previous unprecedented spending with boards and executives now asking what they have achieved?
I had an interesting conversation recently about security and the costs involved to provide adequate protection, and a statement was made that shocked me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compliance Does NOT Equal Security!</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2021/compliance_not_equal_security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 17:28:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2021/compliance_not_equal_security/</guid>
      <description>When you think about Security for your bank or health care provider, what comes to mind? Is it, my bank is PCI-DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard) compliant, or my Health Care provider is HIPPA (Health Insurance Portability and Account Act)compliant?
If it is you are not alone, but you are fooling yourself if you believe that these certifications alone are sufficient to provide adequate protection.
Compliance is often a requirement by a governing body based on the industry that you are in, and whilst they provide a solid framework, this should not be the end goal of any security program and here is why:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security in the &#34;New Normal&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2021/security_new_normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 09:43:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2021/security_new_normal/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of the COVID-19 crisis, many organizations suddenly transitioned to a remote workforce with an increased focus on servicing customers via digital channels. While this rapid transition occurred, telecommuting&amp;rsquo;s sudden move created some security gaps with employees using insecure devices and networks. Cybercriminals, never wanting to let a crisis go to waste, used well-known attack techniques to capitalize on people&amp;rsquo;s COVID-19 fears. The following are some statistics with regards to COVID-19 cybercrime:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
