<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>change on Learning is a lifelong journey, best traveled with an open mind and a curious heart.</title>
    <link>https://www.nephos.guru/tags/change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in change on Learning is a lifelong journey, best traveled with an open mind and a curious heart.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 01:23:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nephos.guru/tags/change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Failure is Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/failure_is_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 01:23:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2022/failure_is_learning/</guid>
      <description>I am sure that at some point in our lives we have all encountered failure and at this point, it may have felt that it was the worst thing that could happen. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t wish to get into the discussion about what type of failure is best, but from my perspective, I have been using this for the last few months to determine the best course of action for me to learn and how I can integrate failure to deepen learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning... by Failing?</title>
      <link>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2020/winning_by_failing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nephos.guru/posts/2020/winning_by_failing/</guid>
      <description>How adopting a fail fast, fail often, fail smarter approach can lead to success in innovation and transformation “Failure is Awesome; I love to Fail!”
said no one EVER!
When we think of failure it conjures up a range of emotions from inadequacy, worthlessness to why try as I am never going to succeed. This type of self-critical talk is not right for anyone and do you know what, everyone fails (more often than we realise).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
